Uh, we used to talk a lot about everyone
talk about how how many impressions.
When we fired the spokes candies a few
Super Bowls ago, it was 25 billion
impressions. So, it's like
three times the global population. It's
like, [laughter] what does that even
mean? And so, you would be quoting these
numbers and thinking, I don't know what
that means for the business. And those
days are over.
>> This is CMO Insider, where you'll get
candid takes on the marketing power
players and power moves. My name's Lara
O'Reilly. I'm a senior correspondent at
Business Insider. I'm joined today by
Rankin Carroll. Rankin is chief brand
officer of Mars Snacking. Rankin, thanks
so much for joining us.
>> Thanks, Lara. Great to be here.
>> thank you so much. So, so you look after
lots of really exciting brands at Mars.
You've been there for what, 23 years, 24
years? Um, so Skittles, Cheez-Its,
Kellogg's, Pringles. And a lot of those
brands only just recently came under
your remit. You recently went through a
very big acquisition, Kellanova,
something like 36 billion dollars coming
into the fold. Can you talk to me about
what it's like looking after a a big
acquisition like that?
>> Um, we've got, you know, strong founder
cultures at both uh, Kellanova, formerly
Kellogg's, W.K. Kellogg, the founder,
and that whole story, 100-year-old,
100-plus-year-old company, combining
with Mars, also over a century old and a
family-owned business, the Mars family.
And I think the thing you've got to
honor the past. You've got brilliant
brands that are they've built themselves
as icons. Pringles or Cheez-It or
Pop-Tarts,
personal favorite, respecting that
culture, respecting that, you know,
brand archaeology, what made these
brands the icons they are, and never
forgetting that. And then remaining
consistent, cuz the worst thing that can
happen is you get, you know, what we
call the new brand manager syndrome is
I'm going to come in and change things.
Well, that would be a
a fatal error. How do you take the
brilliance that you've been gifted, um,
and work with it, and then build it into
some of the systems that have helped us
build success at Mars to help further
them and further them for growth going
forward?
>> Can you give an example of how that
comes life? It's It's kind of hard to
comprehend how that then translates into
someone picking up this candy bar from
the shelf versus another.
>> We believe this
truly getting data at the heart of what
we do, starting with the consumer, and
then multiplying that and enhancing that
through technology
is a game changer for how we think about
uh brand growth.
So, once you accept that but how we
reach consumers
versus big vehicles, big buys that we
used to do, we're now breaking that up
into multiple a multiplicity of reach
vehicles.
>> So, you would do a big TV buy.
>> Yeah, formerly we would have done one
thing, one channel, big reach, and hope
for the best, you know.
>> it for 3 months and then move on to the
next thing.
>> 70% you know, uh 2 plus reach. I think
what we're now doing is finding still
large but more precision around a groups
of audiences. So, we're talking to
multiple groups of audiences and able to
customize and personalize if you will
our con- our content for those
audiences. And that means that our
consumers experience of that will be
depending on who you are, what your
motivations are, uh what your passion
points are, you will see one message
coming from say Snickers.
But if you're in a different group, that
message would be served to you possibly
certainly in a different channel, in a
different uh media, and shaped
differently.
>> So, might something like Snickers be an
example of this? The I remember the
campaign that you did um
around the the Euros, the soccer
tournament with um
Jose Mourinho.
>> We obviously want to build brands with
meaning as we always have. So, great
brands that are consistently delivered
with distinctive distinctive brand
propositions. That will never change.
That is the bedrock of our success as a
company, the bedrock by the way of
Keurig Dr. Pepper success as a company
uh and now combined. But then I think
the big difference is now we need to
personalize at scale. Today's consumers
expect to be able to get involved with a
brand, co-create, have a voice,
participate. Not all of them, but a good
portion of them. If you take those
principles into how we work and use
apply them to the Snickers example you
raised.
>> Yeah, you can you take a step back from
the screen?
>> that was fundamentally starting from
a Snickers play and the fandom. So we
know the behavior around the Euros
around football is banter.
>> I see.
>> So essentially we cloned Jose,
you know,
in partnership with Jose. The the
concept was own goal. So what own goal
what error have you made cuz you're
hungry? Snickers. Um and he would just
give a very special one bit of banter
back to you. And then by the way, you
could send that to your friend, they
could send it on and it just exploded.
So that experience was something we
would never would have done before, but
we had the data, we had the access, we
had the technology capability. And by
the way,
that whole experience in terms of
governance for a company like ours was
quite a journey. You can imagine what
would go in. Um
>> Yeah, user generated content could go
very wrong very quickly.
>> really wrong. [snorts] So it was
remarkable. So it was a big it was a big
step for us because it got us over the
governance
and started to trust ourselves, trust
the technology to take care of things.
And and probably convinced the
organization that we could enter into
these spaces.
>> So talk me through when you're in the
room with whoever it was, the CFO, the
the the legal team,
and you're saying,
"Trust me, this will be fine."
>> We sat with lawyers, with our brand
safety team, with our security team,
um
with the brand team, with the agency
team and and brought that group together
from the beginning. Everything we're
talking about really is about bringing
people together from the beginning so
everyone understands. Cuz you don't show
up and sort of it's a big reveal, tada,
and having 14 people go, "No, you don't.
Like are you crazy?"
>> like the Don Draper doing a
presentation.
>> real anymore.
So so I think you got to bring them
along. Why? Not just to get over the
line because they will contribute. Cuz
we're entering into territories and it
was like the jungle. And so how do we
enter the jungle safely? Well, you bring
experts with you who know what they're
doing. And so, I think this was one of
our earliest pilots. The great news is
we have scaled that. We took it in other
countries. We've also scaled it in other
brands. We did another uh treatment with
WhatsApp and Meta on Twix, which was the
Twix Harmonizer, which again was you
could read in things and it would send
messages to your friends, but harmonize
the bad news um on a voice note. So,
it just was the beginning of us trying
uh different different um
technologies, different uh ways of
entertaining consumers and getting them
involved so they could co-create.
>> And how do you go about measuring that?
With something like a TV campaign,
there's years worth of research and GRPs
and media mix modeling and all and all
of that that goes into measuring whether
a campaign was seen by the people you
wanted to it be seen by. When it's
something like that where there isn't
necessarily, you know, even clicks
perhaps, like how do you go about
working out whether that was a success
or not?
>> Uh we used to talk a lot about everyone
talk about how how how many impressions
you landed. We literally, I think we did
an M&M's when we fired the spokes
candies a few Super Bowls ago, it was 25
billion impressions. So, it's like
three times the global population. He's
like, [laughter] "What does that even
mean?" And so, you would be quoting
these numbers and thinking, "I don't
know what that means for the business."
And those days are over and I think, you
know, impressions or views impressions,
it's hard to qua- quantify the impact of
that. So, what we're working on now, we
had we have a development partnership
with, for instance, a company called
Alembic. So, we're talking about
practically, what does that mean?
Snickers has a partnership with, say,
WWE wrestling in the US.
That has a broadcast. On that broadcast,
the announcer happens to talk about
Snickers. That's that moment gets talked
about in a podcast later on. That leads
to a sale in Texas.
Their LLM can actually get a hold of
tho- that chain of events and start to
attribute value to it. Just to give you
a simple example. There's data science
behind this.
We've had experts check it, so you know
>> say you must have to audit that, right?
>> Yeah,
>> [laughter]
>> of course. But but um
you know, don't trust me, trust the
expert. But But the point is we're
exploring that uh at scale now and
trying to to push into new ways to get a
hold of
truly measuring the business value
created by earned. So, we are working
through connecting all those systems to
try to understand that. And that is that
is
a journey. And by the way, that's what
makes this job so amazing is um we are
in a new age of learning. We are in a
new age of developing our skills. So, if
you're curious, if you have, you know,
uh a bias for learning, it couldn't be a
better time to do what we're doing.
>> Mhm.
And now, a word from our sponsor,
LinkedIn Ads, to talk about how to cut
the bull spend from your marketing
budget.
>> Marketing [music] leaders today are
under more pressure than ever to prove
real impact and concrete [music]
business outcomes. I'm joined by Keith
Browning, Director of Global Brand
Marketing at LinkedIn, to [music] learn
more. What makes LinkedIn uniquely
suited to deliver measurable business
outcomes, especially in B2B?
>> LinkedIn is the largest professional
network in the world, so we're built for
this. We're built for B2B. So, that
means firstly being able to find the
right people. So, you know, you can
target by job title or seniority,
company, etc. But there's also the
professional context component as well.
So, people come to LinkedIn to to learn,
to evaluate potential solutions, and
certainly to make buying decisions as
well.
>> I wanted to talk about you you mentioned
M&M's and firing your your spokes
candies. Now, I wanted to talk about
some of the times when you've taken
maybe a bit of a risk creatively as a
marketer. So, um a couple of years ago,
um M&M's kind of leaned into the the
more kind of like diverse side of of its
brand,
and it touched a nerve in the US, and
there was a the
Um
can you talk me through that story, but
also
how you reacted, or maybe actually on to
the contrary,
when you decided not to react and not to
immediately pull or or or immediately
back down.
>> First of all, we are custodians of
iconic brands and they're, by the way,
owned by a family business.
So, you are very conscious of your
responsibility in that regard. So, risk
taking, it's easy to talk about risk,
but these are assets in someone's family
assets.
And so, when you enter into things like
this, you want to be resonant in culture
and possibly a little bit provocative.
But, provocation in the context of who
you are as a brand. And I think where
brands get into troubles when they step
out of their lane, they step into areas
where why are you even in this
conversation? Um, versus in that
example,
>> So, the example was
>> Yeah, when we the example of a when we
fired the spokes candies
and there was a reaction to that.
I think we could have
taken ourselves a bit seriously and
taken it more seriously than an an M&M's
character ever would
>> [snorts]
>> and reacted in a certain way, but I
think what we did instead was we had fun
with it. And we responded with Green
tweeting,
"Did my shoes just break the internet?"
>> Yeah.
>> Instead of saying getting sort of a
little bit on our soapbox or etc. So, I
think we reacted in a way that M&M's
would.
>> But, I think also in in, you know,
politically charged times and when
consumers are feeling the hit on their
wallet,
sometimes marketers can opt to play it
safe and not
want to take risks. And so, it seemed
like you kind of zigged where where
others zagged at that point.
>> Um,
yeah, listen, I I think we I come back
to I think we try to do what the brand
would do naturally and stay in character
and stay in voice. The same thing is
true of, if I look at Skittles and the
support for LGBTQ, we've been doing that
for going on 10 years. Doing what comes
naturally, continuing a behavior you've
established over time,
you know, you've built the expectation.
You've built who you It's part of who
you are as a brand. So,
cuz I think sometimes brands would
launch into things for maybe good
reasons,
but not have done the scoping of what
could How could this play out?
Um
cuz you don't want to be there kind of
holding the bag going, "Where are we
going now?" Cuz that's the worst place
to be, obviously.
>> Right. And then it's the apology tweet
and the ending the campaign or whatever
and nobody ends up looking good.
>> So, I don't I just don't think we've
entered into areas that are high risk.
>> Mhm.
>> Cuz it's it's easy to say take risks as
a brand as a brand leader. Well, what
does that really mean?
>> A lot of marketers that I speak to at
the moment um are talking about how
difficult it has become to cut through
uh on digital, particularly on social
media.
>> I think what's critical to cut through
is it's still a game of compelling
stories.
So, whatever media, whatever whatever
social platform you're in, if you are
not creating experiences that are
compelling, enjoyable, entertaining. I
think that's a word that we've slightly
forgotten about.
Entertainment. People are still looking
for content that
takes their, you know, captures their
attention. I don't want to steal their
attention.
>> Right.
>> Cuz it's their attention.
>> And you have fun brands, right? Like
you've got to put fairly a lot of really
fun brands that you can play around
with.
>> it's you know, whether it's what we do
on Skittles, whether we are making a uh
giving you the opportunity to win the
experience of having a commercial made
in your front yard.
Well, that's a bit of fun. Um or we are,
as I say, creating an experience for you
to send some banter to your mates around
football. So, it's going into their
passion points. It's going into their
lives and saying, "We can bring
something to you."
Is real But that's a big move for a
company like ours. You have to let go.
But we're getting more confident in
doing that. So, I think it's building a
that is okay with that.
Creating the guidelines and the
guardrails to protect your brand as you
do that. But then being bold and being
ambitious and piloting piloting your way
into things that you can actually scale.
>> And talking about kind of loosening the
leash around the brand a little bit. How
does that fit into things like your
influencer marketing strategy? How are
you building a program around that?
>> Um it took a while for us to go
profession like influencers aren't just
it's not just a wild west. I think it
started a bit like the wild
>> Well, just DMing people
>> Yeah. and just saying hey have a go. Uh
they're professional. They're they're
contracted and they're starting to be
represented by by, you know, um they're
getting consolidating, bringing together
uh in different organizations including
our agency partners.
Um so, they're becoming another channel,
another way to engage with the consumer
and we know
fortunately [clears throat] or
unfortunately
consumers trust influencers more than
they trust brands. So, if we are working
with them um
and they authentically believe in what
the brand's doing, what the brand's
saying, they become advocates for us.
So, understanding those relationships
and finding ways to work with them and
giving them the ability to open up and
co-create and create things that are
relevant for their channels in their own
voice. What does that look like and how
are we building? So, we did a thing in
Germany with an influencer there that
actually launched a song that was in the
top 10 in Spotify um linked to Extra
gum, which is remarkable. But so so
that's just one simple example of going
through a new media, if you will,
through an influencer in a way that was
relevant for her audience that really
was a very positive thing for our brand.
>> And now a word from our sponsor,
LinkedIn Ads, to talk about how to cut
the bull spend from your marketing
budget.
>> LinkedIn's Cut the Bull Spend campaign
urges marketers to rethink how they
evaluate performance and where their
budgets actually drive impact. [music]
I'm here with Keith Browning, Director
of Global brand marketing at LinkedIn,
to learn more.
How do you define [music] bull spend in
practical terms?
>> So, I'd say bull spend is really wasted
advertising spend. It's an investment
that leads to a great-looking dashboard.
So, the numbers look good, the arrows
are going in the right direction, but
really it's not actually doing anything
to to drive the business forward, so it
doesn't hold up to scrutiny.
>> How does LinkedIn help marketers reduce
waste and increase efficiency in real
terms?
>> At LinkedIn, you don't have to pay for
attention from people who you know are
never going to buy from you. A mass
reach works great if you're selling
breakfast cereal, not so much if you're
selling, you know, CRMs. That's really
where LinkedIn is different.
>> We've touched upon AI a little bit in
our conversation so far, but I'm
interested frankly in how you're using
AI day-to-day. [clears throat] Are you
you vibe coding?
>> [laughter]
>> No, I'm not.
Um No, listen, we we are using it uh
quite actively. It's easy to get caught
up in a shiny new toy and run there
um with abandon. It's exciting, but it's
very dangerous. So, we have to be
careful. So, I I just stress that. So,
we're not sort of with you know, it's
not reckless.
Um that said, I would say that we're
applying it probably in three ways.
In how we manage uh and meet consumers
where they are. Then to the making, the
making of the content. AI is starting to
have immense [clears throat] impact. Our
creativity starts with human beings and
it always will. And I still I I'm
convinced
that so far AI isn't originating
anything. It's replicating what's come
in the past and it does a brilliant job.
And then last thing as I mentioned
earlier, it's coming to measurement. So,
how we are able to measure, that is a
mind-opening space around measuring the
impact of what we do. So, in those
areas, it you know, the the the the
the the media, the making, and the
measurement um
huge impact.
>> And AI in advertising and marketing
brings
all of those opportunities that you just
you just mentioned, but also there's a
lot of anxiousness about kind of things
like job losses and what's that going to
mean for for people in their early stage
of their careers. How are you thinking
about building your teams and nurture
the next next generation of marketing
talent?
>> Yeah, it's an immense responsibility.
Cuz I think the simple equation is you
take out the work well you take out the
people. I don't buy that. I think you
take out the work
that drags people down and elevate and
give them an opportunity to do much more
interesting and creative things. So I
think that the potential is to elevate
what everyone's doing and push everyone
up a level by taking out stuff that
takes up your time and allowing you to
focus on strategic thinking, on
creativity,
um on getting to fresh brilliant ideas
that will engage consumers, and learning
how to use AI. So more time to learn,
more time to understand how to use the
tools at your disposal. I do think the
other side of this though is there's a
risk and the backlash has already
started. So I think if we start
overplaying our AI hands, um that could
result in consumers pushing back. Now, I
don't pretend to have a crystal ball and
how that's going to play out, but in 10
years a marketing role and what we do as
CMOs will have changed utterly. There's
huge advantages.
There's risks that go with it and I
think we have to learn our way through
it.
>> But is it is it changing, for example,
the types of people that you hire or are
you I mean, for example, you said that
you wanted to kind of do away with some
of the drudgery and open people up to
doing the more exciting work. Does that
does that kind of change the mix? How
ideas get presented? How how the work
gets gets kind of farmed out?
>> I think it what's changed is I spend a
lot of time with our digital technology
partners. So the CMO and the CDO
partnering together,
I think that age is upon us and I think
you're seeing people merging those jobs
together and you're seeing CDOs become
CMOs and vice versa. Um I do think also
that young young people coming up
through the company are much more data
savvy, more data capable,
more tech capable and you know reverse
mentoring all those things that's
working to help us
stay on top of things. So they have a
big role in that regard. So actually the
reverse is true. They're not being
pushed out or pushed out and they're
actually coming up and getting more
connectivity.
>> an opportunity to get face time with
someone like you. And what's your advice
for kind of early stage marketers?
There's So someone entering the
profession right now, like what what
would your advice be about what they
should focus on and why they should be
so excited about the the kind of
marketing profession in 2026 and beyond?
>> We're what are we looking for? We're
looking for people who are curious. So
how are you as a young marketer
demonstrating and leveraging your
curiosity?
Having the ambition to try things and
bring them forward in your cuz people
want it. I you know you talk to young
young marketers like why would anyone
want to talk to me? It's like what?
Because you're working on really
important brands, we're working on our
our our precious assets because you are
seeing and experiencing things both as a
consumer and as a marketer that we are
not. So bring that into the
conversation.
>> And in a sentence Rankin, what's what's
the thing you're working on right now
that you're most excited about?
>> Measurement.
Honestly,
working on how we measure the impact of
we have a new media mix, we have new
technology coming to play as we've
talked about.
We are you know exploring, experimenting
and piloting new things. If we get
measurement right, then we can scale
much with much more confidence and much
more
effectiveness.
>> Right, let's get measuring. Rankin,
thank you so much for joining us. Thank
you. Appreciate it.
And thank you for joining us. If you
enjoyed this kind of content, please
like and subscribe to our channel. We
also have lots more CMO interviews,
analysis, news, scoops, all the rest of
it at businessinsider.com.